Inventory of the Faculty and department files, Music Dept., University of California, Berkeley, 1923-1979 (bulk 1925-1955)
Music Library
Faculty and Department Files, Music Dept., University of California, Berkeley,
1923-1979
(bulk 1925-1955)
ARCHIVES MUSIC DEPT 1
University of California (1868-1952). Dept. of Music
Number of containers: 8 boxes
The Music Library Berkeley, California 94720-6000
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
List of Contents
- Part I: Account books (3 unbound ledgers):
  - 1923-1938. Lists of expenditures for books, music, equipment, general assistance, musical instruments, orchestral instruction, etc. 158 pp. (Box Box 1, Folder 1.)
  - 1935-1939. 120 pp. (Folder 2.)
  - 1938-1941. 98 pp. (Folder 3.)
- Part II: Monthly accounts
  (loose account and bookkeeping statements arranged by fiscal year in separate folders. Some correspondence is included.)
  - 1912-1918. (Box Box 1, Folder 4.)
  - 1919-1921. (Folder 5.)
  - 1925-1930. (Folder 6.)
  - 1930-1931. (Folder 7.)
  - 1933-1934. (Folder 8.)
  - 1934-1935. (Folder 9.)
  - 1936-1937. (Folder 10.)
  - 1937-1938. (Folder 11.)
  - 1939-1940. (Folder 12.)
  - 1939-1940. (Folder 13.)
  - 1940-1941. (Folder 14.)
  - 1940-1941. (Folder 15.)
  - 1941-1942. (Folder 16.)
  - 1941-1942. (Folder 17.)
  - 1942-1943. (Folder 18.)
  - 1942-1943. (Folder 19.)
  - 1943-1944. (Folder 20.)
  - 1943-1944. (Folder 21.)
  - 1944-1945. (Folder 22.)
  - 1944-1945. (Folder 23.)
  - 1945-1946. (Folder 24.)
  - 1946-1946. (Folder 25.)
  - 1946-1947. (Folder 26.)
  - 1946-1947. (Folder 27.)
  - 1947-1949. (Folder 28.)
  - 1947-1948. (Folder 29.)
  - 1947-1948. (Folder 30.)
  - 1948-1949. (Folder 31.)
  - 1948-1949. (Folder 32.)
  - 1949-1950. (Folder 33.)
  - 1950-1951. (Folder 34.)
  - 1950-1951. (Folder 35.)
  - 1952-1953. (Folder 36.)
  - 1953-1954. (Folder 37.)
  - 1954-1955. (Folder 38.)
  - 1955-1956. (Folder 39.)
  - 1956-1957. (Folder 40.)
  - 1957-1958. (Folder 41.)
  - 1957-1958. (Folder 42.)
  - 1957-1958. (Folder 43.)
  - 1957-1958. (Folder 44.)
  - 1958-1959. (Folder 45.)
- Part III: University Chorus
  (expenditure statements arranged by fiscal year in separate folders. Some correspondence is included)
  - 1939-1940. (Box Box 1, Folder 46.)
  - 1941-1942. (Folder 47.)
  - 1942-1943. (Folder 48.)
  - 1943-1944. (Folder 49.)
  - 1944-1945. (Folder 50.)
  - 1945-1946. (Folder 51.)
  - 1946-1947. (Folder 52.)
  - 1947-1948. (Folder 53.)
- Part IV: Annual budget requests
  (loose statements arranged by fiscal year in separated folders. Some correspondence is included)
  - 1936-1937. (Box Box 2, Folder 54.)
  - 1937-1938. (Folder 55.)
  - 1938-1939. (Folder 56.)
  - 1939-1940 (Folder 57.)
  - 1939-1941. (Folder 58.)
  - 1940-1941. (Folder 59.)
  - 1941-1943. (Folder 60.)
  - 1941-1942. (Folder 61.)
  - 1943-1945. (Folder 62.)
  - 1942-1943. (Folder 63.)
  - 1943-1944. (Folder 64.)
  - 1944-1945. (Folder 65.)
  - 1945-1946. (Folder 66.)
  - 1945-1947. (Folder 67.)
  - 1946-1947. (Folder 68.)
  - 1947-1949. (Folder 69.)
  - 1947-1948. (Folder 70.)
  - 1948-1949. (Folder 71.)
  - 1949-1950. (Folder 72.)
  - 1949-1950. (Folder 73.)
  - 1950-1951. (Folder 74.)
  - 1950-1951. (Folder 75.)
  - 1951-1952. (Folder 76.)
  - 1951-1952. (Folder 77.)
  - 1952-1953. (Folder 78.)
  - 1952-1953. (Folder 79.)
  - 1953-1954. (Folder 80.)
  - 1953-1954. (Folder 81.)
  - 1943-1944 to 1953-1954. (Folder 82.)
  - 1954-1955. (Folder 83.)
  - 1955-1956. (Folder 84.)
  - 1956-1957. (Folder 85.)
  - 1957-1958. (Folder 86.)
  - 1957-1958. (Folder 87.)
  - 1957. (Folder 88.)
  - 1957-1958. (Folder 89.)
  - 1959. (Folder 90.)
  - 1958-1959. (Folder 91.)
  - 1958-1959. (Folder 92.)
- Part V: Gifts
  (reports of the tender of gifts, letters of acknowledgement, etc.)
  - 1939-1950, various gifts. (Box Box 2, Folder 93.)
  - 1951-1957, various gifts. (Folder 94.)
  - 1939-1944, Alpha Omicron Pi Prize for Choral Composition. (Folder 95.)
  - 1946, Columbia Foundation. (Folder 96.)
  - 1946-1952, Dutton Scholarship Fund. (Folder 98.)
  - 1935, Richard Holbrook collection of phonograph records. (Folder 99.)
  - 1951-1958, Sigma Alpha Iota Grant-In-Aid. (Folder 100.)
  - 1959, Alice Swain Kelly Grant-In-Aid. (Folder 101.)
  - 1942-1947, Lena M. Meyer Fund (Folder 102.)
- Part VI: Phonograph recordings
  (invoices for materials received. No correspondence)
  - 1939-1940. (Box Box 2, Folder 103.)
  - 1939-1940. (Folder 104.)
  - 1941-1942. (Folder 105.)
  - 1943-1944. (Folder 106.)
  - 1943-1944. (Folder 107.)
  - 1945-1946. (Folder 108.)
- Part VII: Personnel Roster, appointments.
  (See correspondence)
  - 1940-1941. (Box Box 2, Folder 109.)
  - 1941-1942. (Folder 110.)
  - 1942-1943. (Folder 111.)
  - 1943-1944. (Folder 112.)
  - 1944-1945. (Folder 113.)
  - 1945-1946. (Folder 114.)
  - 1946-1947. (Folder 115.)
  - 1947-1948. (Folder 116.)
  - 1948-1949. (Folder 117.)
  - 1949-1950. (Folder 118.)
  - 1950-1951. (Folder 119.)
  - 1951-1952. (Folder 120.)
  - 1952-1953. (Folder 121.)
  - 1953-1954. (Folder 122.)
  - 1954-1955. (Folder 123.)
  - 1955-1956. (Folder 124.)
  - 1956-1957. (Folder 125.)
  - 1957-1958. (Folder 126.)
  - 1958-1959. (Folder 127.)
  - 1959. (Folder 128.)
- Part VIII: Library materials
  (invoices for books, music, and recordings received, Some correspondence)
  - 1924-1929. (Box Box 3, Folder 129.)
  - 1930-1931. (Folder 130.)
  - 1931-1932. (Folder 131.)
  - 1932-1933. (Folder 132.)
  - 1933-1934. (Folder 133.)
  - 1935-1936. (Folder 134.)
  - 1936-1937. (Folder 135.)
  - 1937-1938. (Folder 136.)
  - 1938-1939. (Folder 137.)
  - 1939-1940. (Folder 138.)
  - 1940-1941. (Folder 139.)
  - 1941-1942. (Folder 140.)
  - 1942-1943. (Folder 141.)
  - 1943-1944. (Folder 142.)
  - 1944-1945. (Folder 143.)
  - 1945-1946. (Folder 144.)
  - 1946-1947. (Folder 145.)
  - 1947-1948. (Folder 146.)
  - 1948-1949. (Folder 147.)
- Part IX: Music dissertations
  - 1921-1948, a list of dissertations in music completed at the University of California at Berkeley. (Box Box 4, Folder 148.)
- Part X: Special events
  - November 4, 1936 to October 21, 1947, guest lecturers in music at the University of California. A correspondence file. (Box Box 4, Folder 149.)
  - 1958-1959, Music Conference lectures. (Folder 150.)
  - October 27, 1959, Soviet composers visit Berkeley. (Folder 151.)
  - 1940-1948, Friends of Music. Correspondence file. (Folder 152.)
  - 1945, Modern Music Magazine, correspondence. (Folder 153.)
  - 1946-1947, National Association of Music Executives of Universities. Correspondence file. Pablo Casals master class 25 16mm films at Pacific Archive (642-1437). (Folder 154.)
- Part XI: Performance organizations on campus
  - 1909-1934, Berkeley Musical Association. Correspondence file. (Box Box 4, Folder 155.)
  - 1940-1941, Composer's Forum. Programs and correspondence. (Folder 156.)
  - 1948-1955, Griller Quartet. Correspondence file and biography of the Griller Quartet. (Folder 157.)
  - 1958, Northern California High Schools Honor Orchestra. Master list, brochures, correspondence. (Folder 158.)
  - 1941-1942, International Society for Contemporary Music Festival at Berkeley. Correspondence file, newspaper clippings, program. (Folder 159.)
  - 1938-1942, League of Composers. Correspondence file including a substantial number of letters to and from Mrs. Claire R. Reis, the national chairman. This file is of historical importance. (Folder 160.)
  - 1959-1961, Opera Workshop. Correspondence file, with special reference to the performance of Benjamin Britten's Turn of the Screw (Devember 10-12, 1959: and Ernest Bloch's Macbeth (March 31, 1960). This file also contains an interesting list of past opera productions at Berkeley (Folder 161.)
    - March, 1942, Gay-Pepusch, The Beggar's Opera, 4 performances
    - February, 1946, Purcell, Dido and Aeneas, 6 perf.
    - April, 1947, Stravinsky, story of a Soldier, 6 perf.
    - April, 1947, Sessions, Trial of Lucullus, 6 perf.
    - May, 1953, Schenk, The Village Barber, 6 perf.
    - May, 1957, Monteverdi, Orfoe, Act II, 3 perf.
    - May, 1957, Elston, Sweeney Agonistes, 3 perf.
    - May, 1958, Elston, Love of Don Perlimplin, 2 perf.
    - May, 1959, Milhaud, Sorrows of Orpheus, 3 perf.
  - 1945-1948, Pro Arte Quartet, correspondence file with brochures. (Folder 161+.)
  - 1950-1951, ASUC Band. Correspondence file, newspaper clippings, etc. (Folder 162.)
  - 1935-1945, UC Symphony orchestra. Correspondence file. (Folder 163.)
  - 1948-1954, UC Symphony orchestra. Correspondence file. (Folder 164.)
  - 1958-1960, UC Symphony orchestra. Correspondence file. (Folder 165.)
  - 1941-1942, UC Quartet Club. Membership lists, programs, some correspondence. (Folder 166.)
  - 1939-1940, University of California String Quartet. Correspondence, programs. (Folder 167.)
- Part XII: Festivals and concerts.
  - 1940-1948, concerts sponsored ny the Coolidge Foundation. Correspondence file. (Box Box 4, Folder 168.)
  - 1941, Berkeley Festival in the Greek Theatre. Correspondence file. (Folder 169.)
  - 1942, short wave programs saluting the University of Chile, 100th anniversary. Correspondence file. (Folder 170.)
  - 1945-1946, performance of Purcell's Dido and Aeneas. Correspondence file. (Folder 171.)
  - 1947, performance Sessions' Trial of Lucullus. Correspondence file. (Folder 172.)
  - 1947, performance of Stravinsky's Histoire du Soldat. Correspondence file. (Folder 173.)
  - 1951-1954, performance of Schenk's The Village Barber. Correspondence file. (Folder 174.)
  - 1955-1956, Festival commemorating the 200th anniversary of the birth of Mozart. Some programs and lists. (Folder 175.)
- Part XIII: May T. Morrison Music Building.
  - 1951-1958, meetings of the Building Committee, reports, some correspondence. (Box Box 4, Folder 176.)
- Part XIV: The May T. Morrison Music Festival, April-May, 1958.
  - 1957-1958, Budget reports, correspondence, agendas, dedication talks, invitation and mailing lists, schedules, press relations, etc. (Box Box 4, Folder 177-194.)
- Part XV: Instruments
  - 1951-1953, The John Challis harpsichord (correspondence file, budget, newspaper clippings). (Box Box 5, Folder 195.)
  - 1961-1963, The Eric Herz harpsichord, on loan to the Deaprtment of Music. Correspondence file. (Folder 196.)
  - 1961-1962, The Hubbard and Dowd harpsichord and the sale of the John Challis harpsichord. Correspondence file. (Folder 197.)
  - 1953-1970, The Walter Holtkamp Organ. Correspondence files, memos, blueprints,photographs, specifications, etc. (Folder 198-200)
- Part XVI: Proposed affiliation between the San Francisco Conservatory of Music and the Department of Music, University of California at Berkeley
  - 1941-1954, Extensive correspondence files, reports, memos, curriculum studies, etc. (Box Box 5, Folder 201-208)
- Part XVII: Individual Persons.
  Files containing a wide variety of documents, particularly correspondence
  - 1950-1951, Abraham, Gerald. Invitation to teach at Berkeley, miscellaneous correspondence concerning appointment to teach. (Box Box 5, Folder 209-209a.)
  - 1948-1952, Abraham, Peter. Materials relating to his collecting of music of the California Native Americans. (Folder 210-212.)
  - 1967, Aird, Donald. Various Programs from concerts. (Folder 212a.)
  - 1938-1951, Bacon, Ernest. Performances, various correspondence. (Folder 213.)
  - 1951-1955, Bacon, Madi. Bio-bibliographical information, correspondence concerning appointment to teach at Berkeley. (Folder 213a-213b.)
  - 1965-1970, Bailey, George. Correspondence, bio-bibliographical records. (Folder 213c.)
  - 1965-1970, Bailey, Robert. Miscellaneous correspondence. (Folder 213d-213f.)
  - 1965-1971, Barrett, Estelle Caen. Correspondence concerning appointment and reappointment to her position at Berkeley. (Folder 213g.)
  - 1947-1957, Bellugi, Piero. Bio-bibliographical information, newspaper clippings, programs, budget data concering a promotion. (Folder 213h-213j.)
  - 1950-1958, Berdahl, James Ernest. Miscellaneous correspondence, budget data concerning leave, programs, and clippings. (Folder 213k-213p.)
  - 1938-1943, 1958, Bliss, Arthur. Invitaton to teach at Berkeley, curriculum vita, performance of Lady of Shalott, etc. (Folder 214-215a.)
  - 1943-1963, Bloch, Ernest. List of classes taught at Berkeley, rosters of students, Ernest Bloch Society letter. (Folder 216-216a.)
  - 1940-1974, Boyden, David Dodge. Bio-bibliographical information, clippings, budget data, and student evaluations. (Folder 216b-216f.)
  - 1957-1978, Briggs, Robert Orlando. Letters concerning his appointment to teach, programs of performances, other miscellaneous correspondence. (Folder 216g.)
  - 1975, Brown, Earle. Correspondence, programs from performances. (Folder 216h.)
  - 1930-1940, Brown, Elizabeth Stuart. Miscellaneous pertaining to classes, notice of her death. (Folder 217.)
  - 1973, Brueggen, Frans. Curriculum vitae and miscellaneous correspondence. (Folder 217a.)
  - 1967, Bylsma, Anne. Bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 217b.)
  - 1959-1963, Casals, Pablo. Correspondence mainly about his master class. 25 16mm films at the Pacific Film Archive. (Folder 218.)
  - 1942, Chavez, Carlos. Invitation to teach at Berkeley. Curriculum vita. (Folder 219.)
  - 1959-1976, Clark, Jacqueline. Bio-bibliographic information, student letters, budget data, and miscellaneous correspondence. (Folder 219a-219d.)
  - 1959-1965, Commanday, Robert Paul. Correspondence concerning his appointment to teach at Berkeley, bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 219e.)
  - 1939-1966, Denny, William D. Budget data, bio-bibliographical updates, programs, original copies of student letters, other correspondence. (Box Box 6, Folder 219f-219l.)
  - 1979-1980, Donatti, Franco, Chair of Italian Culture. Programs and clippings, letters concerning appointment. (Folder 219m.)
  - 1956, Doyle, Althea. Budget data. (Folder 219n.)
  - 1974-1978, Duckles, Vincent Harris. Miscellaneous materials, correspondence, budget data. (Folder 219o-219r.)
  - 1958-1960, Edwall, Harry R. Matters concerning his research grant pertaining to the microfilming of Haydn MSS, bio-bibliographical. (Folder 220-220a.)
  - 1939-1940, Einstein, Alfred. Various correspondences. (Folder 221.)
  - 1965-1968, Eloy Jean Claude. Clippings and bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 221a-221b.)
  - 1957-1972, Elston, Arnold. Bio-bibliographical information and updates, personal materials, budget data. (Folder 221c-221g.)
  - 1997, Feliciano, Richard. Interview in World Harp Congress Review. (Folder 221h.)
  - 1939-1951, Green, Ray. Wide range of correspondence with Albert Elkus, curriculum vita. (Folder 222.)
  - 1948-1952, Griller, Sydney. Correspondence. (Folder 222a.)
  - 1948-1955, Griller Quartet, The. General correspondence (1948-1952), budget data, general correspondence (1952-1955), concerning salary (1950), revision of contract (FTE), second three year contract (1952-1955), first three year contract (1948-1952), and bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 222b-222i.)
  - 1948-1955, Grillers. Correspondence. (Folder 222j.)
  - 1982-1985, Grisley, Gerard. Supporting materials, bio-biliographical information, correspondence concerning appointment and promotion. (Folder 222k-222q.)
  - 1954-1955, Gurvin, Olav. Correspondence with Manfred Bukofzer. (Folder 223.)
  - no date, Heartz, Daniel. (Folder 223a.)
  - 1936-1951, Herzog, George. Miscellaneous correspondence. (Folder 224.)
  - no date, Hertz, Alfred. Excerpts form the will of Alfred Hertz pertaining to the department of Music at Berkeley. (Folder 225.)
  - 1962-1963, Hertzmann, Erich, Evelyn C. Letters concerning death of EH, budget data and correspondence of E. Hertzmann. (Folder 225a.)
  - 1945-1947, Hiatt, Iva Dee. Performances, photographs, correspondence, curriculum vita, bio-bibliographical updates. (Folder 226-226a.)
  - 1960-1966, Hunter, George. Concerning appointment to teach at Berkeley, correspondence. (Folder 226b.)
  - 1952-1969, Jones, Mary Groom. Bio-bibliographical information, programs from performances. (Folder 226c.)
  - 1981-1983, Keller, Michael A. Correspondence, letters from students concerning promotion to academic rank. (Folder 226d.)
  - 1954-1955, Kinkeldey, Otto. Correspondence file. (Folder 226e.)
  - 1962-1965, Kirkpatrick, Ralph. Correspondence, converts, lectures, workshop. (Folder 226f-226i.)
  - 1958-1959, Kolisch, Rudolf. Correspondence with Joseph Kerman. (Folder 227.)
  - 1948-1958, Krieger, Reginald. Bio-bibliographical information, budget data. (Folder 227a-227b.)
  - 1950-1955, Kubitschek, Ernest. Bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 227c.)
  - 1952-1956, Kyme, George. Bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 227d.)
  - 1946-1956, Lawton, Edward B. Miscellaneous, budget data. (Folder 227e.)
  - 1961-1968, Lewin, David B. Bio-biliographical information, budget data. (Box Box 7, Folder 227f-227h.)
  - 1958-1963, Lord, Jewel Wilfred. Budget data. (Folder 227i.)
  - 1956-1961, Lowinsky, Edward E. Bio-bibliographical information, budget data. Special budget data (appointment as visiting professor 1956-1957), supporting materials. (Folder 227j-227n.)
  - 1955, Lyon, Margaret and Margaret Prall. Death of Miss Prall. (Folder 228.)
  - 1953-1954, May, Elizabeth Downey. Various Correspondence with Joaquin Nin-Culmell. (Folder 229.)
  - 1943, Monteux, Pierre. Defense of his performances of modern music by the San Francisco Symphony. Newpaper clippings, correspondence by Albert Elkus, Daily Californian Editorial. (Folder 230.)
  - 1948, Morton, Lawrnece. Correspondence with Manfred Bukofzer. (Folder 231.)
  - 1953-1956, Moulthrop, Frances Anna. Bio-bibliographical information, updates. (Folder 231a.)
  - 1951-1972, Nin-Culmell, Joaquin. Bio-bibliographical information, programs, clippings, replacement. (Folder 231b-231e.)
  - 1946-1950, Nollner, Walter. Curriculum vita, teaching, correspondence. (Folder 232.)
  - 1948, Petran, Laurence. Correspondence with Manfred Bukofzer. (Folder 233.)
  - 1952-1965, Petray, Mrjorie Gear. Bio-bibliographical information, programs and clippings, budget data. (Folder 233a-233d.)
  - 1959-1966, Popper, Jan. Miscellaneous bio-biliographical information, correspondence. (Folder 233e-233f.)
  - 1951-1955, Ringer, Alexander. Bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 233g.)
  - 1948-1952, Rosen, Gerome W. Bio-bibliographical information, clippings, programs. (Folder 233h.)
  - 1963, Rubin, Nathan. Limited bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 233i.)
  - 1952, Salz, Ansley K. Concerning paintings by Piazzoni. (Folder 234.)
  - 1963, Sanks, Mary. Bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 234a.)
  - 1956, Sachs, Curt. Correspondence relating to his Hitchcock lectures. (Folder 235.)
  - 1952, Saphir, Severin Franz. Bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 235a.)
  - 1939-1944, Schoenberg, Arnold. Correspondence by Albert Elkus about Arnold Schoenberg, the death of Carl Engel, etc. (Folder 236-237.)
  - 1946-1953, Sessions, Roger. Mainly bio-bibliographical information, some correspondence, some newspaper reviews, the Bloch professorship. (Folder 238-241c.)
  - 1954-1972, Sherman, Abe. Bio-biliographical information, student evaluations, budget data. (Folder 241d-241f.)
  - 1950-1956, Shifrin, Seymour Jack. Budget data, bio-bibliographical information. (Folder 241g-241i.)
  - 1949-1974, Sparks, Edgaer H. List of professional activities, clipings, reviews. (Folder 241j-241o.)
  - 1979, Stine, Robert E. Bio-bibliographical informatoin, student evaluations, budget data. (Folder 241p-241r.)
  - 1937-1939, Stricklin, Edward G. Correspondence, class matters, curriculum vita, memorial upon his death, Jan.2, 1950. (Folder 242-245.)
  - 1938-1939, Thompson, Randall. Correspondence. (Folder 246.)
- Part XVIII: Manfred Bukofzer
  - Bio-bibliographical materials. Extensive information. (Box Box 7, Folder 247-252.)
  - Bio-bibliographical materials. Extensive information. (Box Box 8, Folder 253-259.)
  - 1941-1955, 212 letters (indexed) pertaining to Manfred Bukofzer's musicological activities. (Folder 260-262.)
  - 1941-1955, Departmental matters: principally correspondence and memos. (Folder 263-267.)
  - 1941-1955, Graduate matters: principally recommendations, examinations,enrollmentlists, correspondence, scholarships, committee meetings. (Folder 268-280.)
  - 1941-1955, Matters dealing with professional associations: American Council of Learned Societies, American Musicological Society, Music Library Association, International Congress of Musicology, Music Teachers National Association, RISM, etc. (Folder 281-290.)
- Part XIX: Albert Elkus
  - In memorium file. (Box Box 8, Folder 291.)
  - Bio-bibliographical material. (Folder 292.)
  - 1930-1950, Appointment to Faculty of Music, appointment as chairman, reappointments as chairman, retirement plans. (Folder 293-293b.)
  - 1931-1936, Courses taught at the University of California. (Folder 294.)
  - 1941-1950, Fybate lecture notes for Music 27A (Folder 295.)
  - 1938-1950, Music 27A-B,examinations given from 1938-1950. (Folder 296.)
  - 1939-1950, Miscellaneous correspondence. (Folder 297a.)
  - 1942-1950, Travel reports. (Folder 298.)
  - 1939-1940, Theses committees. (Folder 299.)
  - 1940-1941, Committee: Council of the Humanties. Extensive file. (Folder 300.)
  - 1940-1941, Committee: University appointments. (Folder 301.)
  - 1935-1950, Committee: University honorary degrees. (Folder 302.)
  - 1946-1950, Committee: Classroom building. (Folder 303.)
  - 1948-1949, Committee: Art-Decorative Art Departments. (Folder 304.)
  - 1943-1950, Committee: University songs and rallies. (Folder 305.)
  - 1948-1949, Committee: Advisory Committee on Performed Music. (Folder 306.)
  - 1945-1950, Comittee: Affiliation with Secondary Schools. (Folder 307.)
  - 1936-1941, W.P.A.: National Youth Administration. (Folder 308.)